CURRICULUM VITAE

NAME : IMWENE KENNEDY OMUKADA,

ADDRESS : **PO BOX 325-50408**,

Kamuriai- Kenya,

MOBILE NO : 0721-644971, 0729-459364 E-mail ADDRESS : imwene2000@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a bachelor of science Analytical Chemistry graduate from the University of Nairobi with an ongoing Master's degree in Analytical Chemistry with specialized knowledge of principles of analytical Chemistry methods, and techniques. I am an accomplished Analytical chemist with a solid history of achievement in Agricultural, Animal products and environmental analysis. Areas of expertise include chromatographic methods, spectroscopic methods and classical techniques.

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

To gain knowledge and practical skills to become an efficient and all-round professional in a reputable and growing organization as well as be resourceful, competent and exemplary at work.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

Sep 2019-Date : UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

MSc. Analytical Chemistry-(On-going).

2014 -2018 : UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

BSc. Analytical Chemistry Second Upper Division

2002 - 2005 : S. A KOLANYA BOYS HIGH SCHOOL

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KSCE)

1994 - 2002 : KAMOLO PRIMARY SCHOOL

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (KCPE)

SOFT SKILLS:

Teamwork

- Member of the UNICSA-University of Nairobi (2015-2018).
- Both Graduate and Undergraduate Research student. (2018-Present)
- Participated in Church Choir competition at Ridgeways Catholic Church-2020

Organizational;

Successfully combining study, part time work and extracurricular activities.

Communication:

• Report writing, seminar slides presentations for my university course and briefing/inducting the attaches, new interns and visitors.

Analytical thinking;

- Applying statistical and numerical techniques to process data.
- Data interpretation and forming structured arguments supported by evidence.

WORK AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

(1) November, 2019- Date: Central Veterinary Laboratory (CVL), Analytical Chemistry and Food Safety Laboratory- Kabete.

Post: (Public service commission internship program)-Analytical Chemist/Analyst.

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Toxicology and Aflatoxin Analysis.
- Pesticide Residue and Antibiotic Analysis.
- Heavy metal Analysis.
- Veterinary drugs analysis

(2) Jan, 2019-Nov,2019 : Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service (KEPHIS)

Post: Analytical Chemist

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Analysis of pesticides MRLs on fresh produce.
- Analysis of water for irrigation suitability
- Analysis of organic and inorganic trace contaminants in plants, soil, crops, water and animal produce.
- Analysis of organic and inorganic ingredients in agro-inputs.
- Analysis of aflatoxin in cereals, nuts and Tea matrices.

(3) Feb, 2011 – April 2011 : Mumias Sugar Company Limited

Post: Attachment

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Working in accordance of GLP, GMP and SOP requirements.
- Preparation of primary, Stock and Working standards.
- Analytical balances and Critical volumetric glassware verification.
- Sample Collection, Preservation, Preparation, Extraction.

WORKSHOP AND TRAINING ATTENDED:

- 1. 3rd Phytosanitary Conference (Virtual Edition) 13th -16th September 2021-KEPHIS
- 2. Nuclear Magnetic Resonance training at the Kenya National-NMR Center, University of Nairobi, Kenya August, 2021.
- 3. African Material Research Society Conference on Nanotechnology Webinar August 2021
- 4. Workshop on Pan- African Covid-19 and Food Safety Webinar supported by University of Nairobi and the Institute for Food Safety at Cornell University, April 2021.
- 5. Trained on Spectroscopic techniques (ICP-MS and ICP-OES), GFAAS, FAAS, CV-AAS at Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service-KEPHIS Headquarters.

- 6. LC-MS/MS, GC-MS/MS, GC-MS, GC-Detectors and UHPLC training at Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service Headquarters.
- 7. Training on HPTLC and ELISA screening at Directorate of veterinary services Labs
- 8. Data Analysis using Minitab 17/19, Microsoft Excel and JMP-(SAS).

OTHER PROFESSIONAL SKILLS ACQUIRED:

2020: Digital Program Ministry of ICT.

Data management/Entry and Virtual Assistant training by Ajira

2014: Driving License (DL No: 1907035-YVS 196)

Class B C E -Experience: Seven (7) years.

2010: Egerton University, Department of Engineering

Computer Packages Certificate

Research Work Completed:

Analysis of Heavy Metals in Selected Foodstuffs from Different Estates in Nairobi Metropolitan Area. University of Nairobi, Chemistry Department-Pesticide Research Laboratory. (Undergraduate research work)

Resource Recovery: Use of Microbial Fuel Cells in Electricity Production from Fruit Waste in Nairobi Kenya. (Master's Thesis due for Submission)

Current and Voltage data logging from Microbial Fuel Cells using ARDUINO BASEDSENSORS. (Research paper submitted for publication)

Research papers:

Biotransformation of Biodegraded Organic waste from a Batch mode Microbial Fuel Cell to organic fertilizer- on going.

Kinetic Modelling of Microbial Fuel Cells Voltage data from market wastes in Nairobi City Kenya- on going.

Resource Recovery: Use of Microbial Fuel Cells in Electricity Production from Fruit Waste in Nairobi Kenya- on going.

Research Interest:

Analytical Chemistry and nanoscience

REFERENCES:

1 Dr. Kenneth Orengo

Head of Analytical Chemistry and Food Safety Lab

P.O BOX 00625, Kangemi

Directorate of Veterinary Services-Kabete

Cell phone: +254721274827

E-mail: orengootieno@gmail.com

2 Dr. Damaris N. Mbui (Ph.D.)

Senior Lecturer,

P.O BOX 30197-00100, Nairobi, Kenya

Chemistry Department, University of Nairobi

Cell phone: +254723322033 E-mail: dmbui@uonbi.ac.ke

3 Mr. Peter Kamuti

Head of Analytical Chemistry and Food Safety Lab

P.O BOX 49592-00100, Nairobi, Kenya

Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Services

Cell phone: +254720259617 E-mail: pkamuti@kephis.org